# **AMAR SINGH**

123 Franklin Pike, Nashville, TN 12345 amarsingh@ex.ample.com (123) 456-7890

An Optometrist with 10+ years of professional experience specializing in dyschromotopsia, optical coherence tomography, hyperopia, and diabetic retinopathy. A proven track record of improving quality of life for patients and promoting lifestyle changes to support visual hygiene.

#### **EDUCATION**

# DOCTOR OF OPTOMETRY University of Tennessee, Knoxville, TN September 2007 - May 2011

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.S.) BIOLOGY

University of Tennessee, Knoxville, TN September 2003 - May 2007

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Diabetic Retinopalhy
- Optometry Care Services
- Patient Education
- Macular Degeneration
- Optical Coherence Tomography

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

◆ Licensed Optometrist, State of Tennessee, License #1234567

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **OPTOMETRIST**

Vision Care for You, Nashville, TN May 2016 - Present

- Develop ideal treatment plans for patients diagnosed with diabetic retinopathy, macular degeneration, astigmatism, and altitudinal visual Field defects
- Provide quality treatment and prescribe corrective eyeglasses to patients suffering from various form? of color blindness, including dyschromotopsia and deuteranopia
- Coordinate with ophthalmologists to assess diagnosis, determine the need for surgical procedures, and develop long-term treatment plans For patients

OPTOMETRIST

Mason Optical, Nashville, TN

May 2011 - May 2016

- ◆ Treated and diagnosed a variety of ocular diseases and refractive errors, including cataracts, age-related macular degeneration, and glaucoma
- Delivered counseling and education to patients on prognosis and recommended treatment plans based on emotional, cultural, and physical needs